翻译+校对 - 遗落星痕 Ice北极熊
时间轴 - Ice 北极熊
Hey, friends!
嘿，朋友们
All right, so we have made a console app.
现在我们已经制作了一个控制台应用
We have explored the documentation.We've installed the .NET Core SDK and Visual Studio Code.
我们也浏览了文档，并且安装了 .NET Core SDK 和 Visual Studio Code
-All right, next, let's make a Web Application -Exactly
-好了，那接下来，我们要制作一个 Web 应用 -没错
All right, so if we look at my screen here,we have the folder that I have my console app.
现在看向我的屏幕，在文件夹中已经有我们的控制台应用了
And so let's so we have to create a brand new folder.
所以我们必须创建一个全新的文件夹
All right. Yeah.
嗯，是这样
I just wanna point out that all that did was a WriteLine, and it output it to the console
我们要做一个什么样的程序呢？最起码应该做到通过 WriteLine ，并把内容输出到控制台
not particularly impressive, there's no web browser here.
但其实这也没啥特殊的，也没有用到浏览器
There's just, Hello Scott.
只是做了一个 Hello Scott
-Yeah, we need to when you're learning about a Web Framework, you want to do something on the web. -Absolutely
-嗯，如果你正在学习 Web 框架的话，你肯定会想通过 Web 做一些有趣的事嘛 -当然喽
So let's do it.
我们一定要搞一个大新闻
I just wanna juxtapose the difference between the two, so let's take a look at that
我想先比较一下这两个程序有啥区别，让我们来看看那个吧
all right?
好吗
So what do you want me to do?
我们应该怎么开始，你有好的建议吗
So can I teach you a new trick?
没准我可以教你一个新的技巧
Let's do it.
可以，来吧
-That you can create your web application and a directory at the same time? -Are you sure?
-你可以在同时创建你的 Web 应用和目录吗 -你确定吗
I can do it.Cuz I like making directories.
可以是可以，但我喜欢直接创建目录
-I know, I know, but like try something new. -All right, all right.
-我知道，但尝试一下新的东西总是好的吧 -对吧
-Try something -new, okay. I'll try
-那来吧 -开始吧
So dotnet new web -o.
dotnet new web -o
And let's call it mywebapp.
起个名字叫 mywebapp 吧
So we, in the previous video,we looked at the different .NET templates that are available.
其实在之前的视频中我们就查看了各类可用的 .N​​ET 模板
Web is just one of the templates. So we looked at console, and now we're looking at web,
Web 只是其中的一个模板，我们已经了解了 console ，现在我们需要看下 web
just for people who might be tuning in now. -Okay.
稍等一下，我觉得有必要等一下屏幕前的小伙伴。 -好的
So hit Enter.
敲下回车
So it says
欸，你看
the template core empty, been created successfully, and it put in a folder called mywebapp.
模板 ASP.NET Core Empty ，已创建成功，并放在了名为 mywebapp 的文件夹中
So I like to go and make the directory, and then go into the directory,
你喜欢先创建目录，然后进入目录
and you're saying I can go -o, it'll make the folder and name the thing,all at the same time At the same time.
但是使用 -o 命令，它会同时创建文件夹和同名项目，这两任务同时给你整好了
And if you think about it
而且你想想
if somebody's following this outside of Windows,the way they created directory there might be a different.
如果有人在 Windows 之外使用这种方法，他们创建目录的方式可能会有所不同
That is a valid point you're right cuz I said, md and they might say, mkdir
说的好，确实是这样，因为我用 md 他们可能会用 mkdir
And that's a good point.
提醒一下小伙伴们
All right, and
好的，还有
when I did that, just as you said, we did a .NET new web.
当我这样做时，就像你说的，我们完成了一个新的 .NET 网站
Which is this one this is an empty one. Anyway there's different web options that we'll explore later.
这个应用并没有包含具体内容。当然还有别的可创建网站的选项，那些我们等会说
But right now we made the simplest possible web application.
但现在我们完成了最简单的 Web 应用
Exactly, just like the step just above a console right at the line. Okay Just right above it
确切的说，创建的时候只用了一行命令就给解决了
We can go into let's go into the mywebapp, and
让我们来看看这个程序，先进入 mywebapp （目录），然后
I see a csproj which makes sense, I see a Program.cs,
我看到了 csproj ，这是必须有的哈，我还看到了 Program.cs
which I had before. But this is something different. I see a Startup.cs and a wwwroot.
之前我们就见过这些文件了，但是这些是与之前不同的。我看到 Startup.cs 和 wwwroot
Now we could poke around here at the command line, but you showed me
现在我们可以在命令行中试一下，但是若能打开
that VS code is better. It's pretty good.
VS Code 就更好了，它是最方便的
It is better, so
完美
let's go into there.Now, this is interesting, by the way, I tagged code dot
让我们在这打开，这就好玩了，顺便说一下，我键入的是 code .
it opened up my web application.
它打开了我的 Web 应用程序目录
It's worth pointing out that if you notice in the background
你看到了没，如果你注意到背景
there, it also opened my previous windows.
在那里，它也打开了我以前的窗口
VS Code likes to put things back the way it was so it's restoring my session.
VS Code 能够记录你的工作状态并且恢复上次的会话
I'm gonna go and close the console app from earlier.
但是我们要先关闭之前的控制台应用
And we'll just say, there's that warning again
欸，它又出现了这种警告
required assets to build, it's totally okay to say yes,
为构建添加所需的资源，这毫无疑问的选 yes
because we wanna be able to debug our web application, all right
因为我们总希望能够调试我们的 Web 应用，对吧
So I noticed you have a couple of things down there
我注意到你在右下角有一些额外的东西
are those additional Yeah, that's a great point.
是那些确实是一个值得关注的地方
So down here, I've got some extensions,these are like a little accordion extensions
在下方这里，我有一些扩展，这些像小手风琴一样的扩展
If I want to play with Docker, or if I'm gonna be using Git, so GitLens and Docker are extensions.
如果我想玩 Docker ，或者如果我要使用 Git ，那么 GitLens 和 Docker 就是所需的扩展
If I click here on the left, you can see my installed extensions,and recommended extensions.
如果我点击左边这里，你可以看到我的安装扩展和推荐的扩展
And I could go and search for extensions here as opposed to using the web.
我可以在这里搜索扩展，而不必使用网页版
Cuz I was just moving them out of the way.
这里我就把他们移开了
All right, cuz I just noticed something different
好的，因为我刚注意到一些不同的东西
so I was asking questions for the people at home.
所以我想帮屏幕前的童鞋问一下
Definitely useful.
不错的提问
So let's just move that out of the way, here we go.
我们先不理它了，继续吧
So Program.cs, this is a little bit bigger than it was before.
Program.cs ，这比以前的稍大一些
Cuz it's bringing a bunch of stuff that if we look at the previous one
因为它多了一堆东西，如果我们对比一下前一个程序
while we putting much only had using systems and maybe IO.
而我们很多时候只使用 systems （指以 System 开头的名称空间），可能还有 IO
Actually, that's a good point, let's open up the csproj.
说的好，我们来打开 csproj 文件
Yeah. If you recall earlier
嗯 你可以回忆下先前的内容
our SDK was Microsoft.NET.Sdk.Web,this is a web application.
而在这我们所用的 SDK 是 Microsoft.NET.Sdk.Web ，这是一个 Web 应用
This is new, indicating that there as a folder called,wwwroot, that we'll talk about in a little bit.
这是新的，还有一个文件夹叫做 wwwroot ，我们稍后再谈它
And we have our first package reference, Asp.NetCore
这是我们第一个引用的包， Asp.NetCore
specifically .All.
注意到是 .All 了吗
So literary everything?
它能包含所有的内容
Right.
没错
Now, it could in fact be listed one item at a time,
现在，它可以把一个个的项目分开
ASP.NET Core broken up in a lot of different pieces.
ASP.NET Core 能分成许多​​不同的部分
So it's kind of a cafeteria plan.
这些都可以随意组合
Okay. This is a package of packages, so rather than having a list of dozens of different
嗯，这是一个由许多小包组成的大包，有些框架包含了几十个包
packages, and having to pick ones I want, ones I don't want
不管我用不用得到，都给集成上了
this makes it much, much simpler.It just gives me everything by default.
当然这也是为了免去麻烦的配置，使得它使用更方便，在默认情况下，它给了我所有的东西
So for learning, it's easier for getting started, it's easier.
对于学习来说，这能使得入门更加简单
If you're familiar with ASP.NET,it's easier because everything you expect is there.
如果您熟悉 ASP.NET 这就更容易了，因为所有你想用的都已经添加上了
I was also, one thing I've also noticed,it is one version now
我也这么觉得，我还注意到了一件事，这里有一个版本号
It's nice and simple, you just say, I want 2.0 and
这点很好呀，也很简单，你只需说，我想要2.0版本
it brings in everything that hangs off of it.
它将决定所有未指定的版本号
Of 2.0, okay
2.0，好吧
I call it a metapackage or a package of packages.
我称之为元包或者由程序包组成的包
I like that term, packages of packages.
我喜欢这个词， package of packages
Yeah, nice and simple.
嗯，简单明了
So if we go into Program.cs, you saw before we had Using System
让我们打开 Program.cs ，你会看到我们之前用过的 System
And when we say Using System, that was what allowed us to type Console.WriteLine cuz System.Console.WriteLine.
在我们键入了 Using System 后，这将允许我们使用 Console.WriteLine 哦不 System.Console.WriteLine
But here this is a web application, and we have other stuff, we've brought in some threading and
但这是一个 Web 应用，并且还加入了其他的东西，我们引入了一些有关线程以及
some IO stuff, but this is the ASP.NET Core stuff that's added.
IO 相关的东西，这些就是 ASP.NET Core 所添加的东西
What's worth pointing out those
值得指出的是
our Main here is different than our console Main.
我们在这里的 Main 和我们控制台中的 Main 不同
Before we had a Console.WriteLine,
之前我们有一个 Console.WriteLine
and that was it.
就是这样
And actually, this is totally off-script
其实，这些都是脚本生成的
which implies of course, that we actually have a script, right?
这当然意味着我们确实有一个脚本，对吧
I wonder if I could do this.
不知道我能不能这么做
Okay, I just have a Main
我就只需要一个 Main
and I've commented out all the web stuff.
我已经把所有与 Web 相关的注释掉了
So, what would happen?
那么，会发生什么
Let's find out.I wonder if it'll work.
让我们来试一试，我想知道它是否能运行
Remember I've typed, control~?
记得我已经按下了键盘， Ctrl + ~
I think it's tilda.I think if you say, tildi
我认为这是波浪号，如果你说， tildi
you might have an accent of some sort, yeah.
你可能就会有某种口音
I think it would be an accent that is completely and
我认为这将是一个彻彻底底的口音
totally incorrect.
且完全不正确
so it actually switched it over to a Console Application.
所以它实际上就像是一个控制台应用
Right. Well, it didn't really switch it over
对的。 其实，它并没有真正地发生改变
because it always was a Console Application.
因为它终究是一个控制台应用
The idea being that they are the same thing, right?
可以把他们当作一样的东西，是吧
A .NET application has a main entry point, and
.NET 应用程序有一个主入口点
then it does some stuff.
然后它能完成一些工作
And I just wanted to kinda juxtapose that it can do some consoley stuff
我只是想说明它可以作为控制台应用
or it can do some webby stuff.
也可以作为 Web 应用
So let's do some webby stuff.
来做一些有关 Web 的程序吧
Like what would it look like out of the box?
就像是开箱即用
Yeah, well, that's a good point.
是的，这很好
So let's go back, dotnet run,
所以让我们回到命令行， dotnet run
this time having changed it to say BuildWebHost.
这次改变后使用了 BuildWebHost
And it's gonna run and build.
它会编译再运行起来
And it says a couple of things.
输出了许多信息呢
It's running in production.
程序正在生产环境中运行
It's listening on localhost:5000, so
正在监听 localhost:5000
we have started a little web server.
我们启动了一个小型的网络服务器
Okay
嗯
Now it says, listening at localhost:5000.
现在它显示，正在监听 localhost:5000
Let's open up browser, and let's localhost:5000 it.
让我们打开浏览器，让我们转到 localhost:5000
Can't you also just click on the link within the terminal?
你是不是可以点击终端内的链接
Yeah, that is a good point.
对，说得好
I guess I could or not.
欸?不能嘛
Or not, okay.
不可以，好吧 （注：其实是可以的，按住 Ctrl 再点击）
I don't know, yes.
我不知道哎
It should.
它应该可以的
It should work.
它应该能这样使用
Except that's Hello World
除了那个 Hello World
That's Hello World!, exactly.
这就是 Hello World! ，确实是这样
So where is that, Hello World, coming from?
那么， Hello World 是从哪里来的
Where is?
等一下
Where is that text?
这些文字从哪里来的
There's the text itself, so.
对，这些文字在哪里
Yeah, let's find out, so let's follow it through.
好的，让我们一起来看看吧
So BuildWebHost passes these arguments in and says .Run.
BuildWebHost 将这些参数传入并执行了 .Run
What does BuildWebHost do?
BuildWebHost 做了些什么
That's right here.
看到这儿
Yep
是的
Looks like it CreatesDefaultBuilder, and then it says, UseStartup.
看起来像 CreatesDefaultBuilder ，然后它调用了 UseStartup
And then And
然后呢
you can see here that the Startup text here is in blue,
你可以在这里看到这里的 Startup 文本是蓝色的
that means it's not a, it's a keyword basically.
这意味着它有些不同，它像是一个关键词
This here, these word, Startup, is telling it used this class.
在这里，这个词 Startup 告诉它使用这个类
This class's name is not magic
这个类的名称并没有什么特别的
if I changed it to Foo, It would not-
如果我将它改为 Foo ， 它会不会
Well, let's find out
好吧，让我们来找出答案
Let's go ahead and change it to Foo,hit dotnet run, See what happens.
让我们将其更改为 Foo 并继续键入 dotnet run ，看看会发生什么
The type or namespace Startup could not be found, okay?
类型或名称空间 Startup 无法找到，这样的吗
But what if I change this to Foo?
那如果我将这个改为 Foo 呢
There we go
让我们来试下
Pause, runs just fine.
它停了一下，运行成功了
The point there being that the name Startup isn't magic.
这里要说的一点是， Startup 这个名字并没有什么特别的
It isn't magic. Right.
这并不是魔术
It does not have to be Startup.
它不一定非要是 Startup
Nope, what it's saying is, again if we look at the docs,
它的意思是，然我们再看看文档吧
and this is what's nice with Visual Studio code,
这对于 Visual Studio Code 来说很方便
it says specify the startup type to be used by the web host.
它表示指定要由 Web 主机使用的启动类型
So it's just saying go and use this class.
所以它只是说去使用这个类
And this class here that we called Startup or Foo, or
像这里我们称之为 Startup 或 Foo 的这个类，或者
whatever, has to be just be shaped a certain way
任意名称，但都必须以正确的形式填入
it has to look a certain way.
它必须是正确的形式
Okay, so you could call it Beyonce
好的，你可以称它为 Beyonce
you could call it anything.
你可以给它任意的名称
Yeah, it has to be a Beyonce.
好，它必须是 Beyonce
I am afraid I should probably have
也许我们有别的选择吧
but we'll just have Beyonce without an accent.
但我们只是用了 Beyonce
And it should work just fine.
它应该运行得很好
Beyonce should be a key word.
Beyonce 应该是一个关键词
It should be.
应该是
A reserved word.
保留字
-It should be, it should be. -But its not, sadly.
-它一定是的。-可惜的是，它并不是
So this is an important point though.
这是非常重要的一点
It's saying use this startup type.
这说使用这种启动类型
And that startup type has to have certain methods.
并且该启动类型必须具有某些方法
So Beyonce, in this case, has to have a method
所以 Beyonce ，在这种情况下，必须有一种方法
called ConfigureServices and one called Configure.
称为 ConfigureServices ，另一个称为 Configure
And that's the requirements for Beyonce in this context for
这就是 Beyonce 在这一上下文中的要求
the startup class.
作为启动类型
So what's going on in these?
那么这些是怎么回事
We've got- And you have the nice little instructions at the top, which I've always appreciated.
在上方我们会有一些提示，这是很赞的功能
Yeah, I like it when templates include a little bit of instruction, a little bit of comments.
是的，当模板包含一些提示或一些注释时会让开发人员很省劲
So this Method it's called by the runtime and
所以这个方法是在运行时调用的
it adds services to a collection called the services collection.
它将服务添加到名为 services 的集合中
And services are just stuff you might wanna use later in your app
而服务是指你稍后想在程序中使用的任意内容
So it could be things like authentication,
可以是认证之类的
so using a service like Facebook or Google, like which we'll
在使用像 Facebook 或 Google 服务的时候，我们可能会用到
look at later dates, but- So if I just type services.,
如果我只是输入 services.
you've got AddAuthentication, AddCaching,
你就能看到 AddAuthentication ， AddCaching
AddIdentity, AddLogin, AddMemory, add whatever.
AddIdentity ， AddLogin ， AddMemory 以及添加任何内容
And even things that don't appear like you pointed out.Like maybe Facebook authentication
甚至一些说不上来的东西，就像 Facebook 认证一样
different kinds of those are all other third party things that could be added on as well.
和这些不同的其他第三方的服务都可以添加上来
So those services get configured here,get added to this collection.
所以这些服务在这里配置并被添加到这个集合中
Yeah. And it's a little confusing
是的，这有点令人疑惑
-because you've got ConfigureServices. -And then you have Configure.
-因为你即有 ConfigureServices -还有 Configure
Like that is something that confused me when I first started.
就像我初学时一样，这让我非常困惑
Yeah, it is confusing.
是的，这是会让人感到困惑
This is the get everything ready
这是为了做好一切准备
load up the collection of stuff I want to play with.
加载我想要使用的程序的集合
And then configure them. Set them up.
然后配置它们，设置好
Like you could've maybe, maybe they could've named it AddServices or DoTheStuffWithTheServices.
你可以像这样命名它： AddServices 或者 DoTheStuffWithTheServices
And then configure them.
然后配置它们
Yeah, okay.
嗯呢
But the point is one is prep your environment, and then do specific things to set your environment up.
但重点在于准备好你的环境，并且然后做特定的事情来设置你的环境
Like, in this case, if we are doing development,not production
就像在这种情况下，如果我们正在进行开发而不是生产
then when you get an exception you'd like a nice friendly page.
那么当你得到一个异常时，你会喜欢上这个友好的页面
Okay, not a page of horror.
嗯嗯，而不是满页的恐惧
Yes, not the scary page.
是的，不是可怕的页面
This here is the app.Run,this is the default cuz you said we wanted to do empty.
这里是 app.Run 这里是默认的，因为你说了我们想要一个空的模板
And you asked where Hello World!, was.
你问了 Hello World! 是来自哪里的
And there it is
它就在那里
There it is.
哦，那就是啊
So we've change that text, and dotnet run.
所以我们已经改变了这个文本，并且运行 dotnet run
It should still run.
它应该仍然可以运行
Now if I come back over here, and notice it still says Hello World!
现在，如果我回到这里，注意它仍然输出了 Hello World!
That's because we haven't hit refresh.
这是因为我们没有刷新
And there it is
看，出现了
Yeah, that's a good one.
是的，这很棒
You like that?
你喜欢这个吗
Excellent. I think the Beyhive would be happy.
太棒了，我认为 Beyhive 将会很开心
They would be.
肯定会呀
Alright, cool.
总之，很酷
This is cool. Mm-hm.
确实很酷
One of the things that, when you are working, so
事情正是如此，当你完成到这里
we've seen hello world or hello Beyhive in honor of Beyonce.
我们已经看见了 Hello world 或者是 Hello Beyhive 以纪念 Beyonce
But as a person who's building their webpage for
但对第一次建立网页的人来说
the very first time, you want to see a page.
你想看到一个页面
Like, you actually want to see something that's a little bit
就像，你实际上想看到一些别的
more than just- A string.
而不仅仅是字符串
Just a string.
仅仅是字符串
Right, and certainly, having a string,
对，当然，若想看到字符串
like doing all of your work inside of a Response.Write is
若你想在 Response.Write 中完成你所有的工作
gonna break down pretty quickly.
你很快就会崩溃的
Yeah. Right.
是这样的
So in the next section, we're going to go an add some pages
所以在下一节中，我们将添加一些页面
and build, take this, and we're gonna start from empty, though.
以及如何构建和运行，我们将从零开始
Yeah. We're not gonna cheat,
是的，我们不会作弊
we're gonna build on top of empty.
我们要建立在零基础之上
So we've seen a console app,
所以我们写了一个控制台应用
we've seen an app that does a single string,
我们已经写了一个应用可以返回单个字符串
next section we'll do pages.
下一节我们将会制做页面
Yes we will.
是的，我们会的！敬请期待